CHAITANYA VARMA MANTENA

4 Gloucester Square, Railway Street, Dublin | 0899888354 | chaitanyavarma.1998@gmail.com

Professional summary

Graduated in MSc. Data analytics and bachelor's in computer science and engineering in span of 5 years. Gained hands on experience in computer-based skills and user experience through smart, strategic thinking that anticipates outcomes. Good in figuring out what makes teams tick, trains and transforms individuals into top performers. Waiting to pursue a challenging career in a progressive organization that lends me the opportunity to grow professionally and enhance my knowledge while allowing me to utilize my skills for the growth of the organization. Currently looking forward for internships and graduate programmes. STAMP 1G holder.

Education

Master of Science: DATA ANALYTICS

2019 - 2020

DUBLIN BUSINESS SCHOOL

DUBLIN

- Machine learning using python
- Data visualization using Tableau and python
- Data Mining using RapidMiner
- Data storage solutions of relational database, data warehouse using Microsoft SQL.

Bachelor of Science: COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2015 - 2019

ANNA UNIVERSITY

CHENNAI

Work history

Sales Assistant

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

SUPERVALU

Dublin, DUBLIN

- Ensuring consistent level of customer service at all times.
- Advising/ persuading customers on purchases/ answering customer queries/ directing customers to location of product.
- Assisted customers with signing up for store loyalty programs and provided details about key benefits.

Sap Hana Internship

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

INTRIGO

CHENNAI, INDIA

- Got used to corporate environment.
- Analyzed departmental documents for appropriate distribution and filing.
- Project on implementation of SAP HANA cloud integration, and generating insights from Data mining algorithm to predict changes in stock prices which is completed as a part of my academic submission furthered my ambition to empower myself with

technologies where the jobs of today exists that are more machine and data-driven.

• Believed that if these technologies are fueling industries, it can fuel my career too.

Android App Development

GRIPTHOR SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS

May 2018-June 2018 HYDERABAD,INDIA

Skills

Technical Skills

- Programming languages:
 C,C++,Java, Python, SQL,R
- Visualization software's: Hands on experience in creating visualizations using Tableau.
- Operating systems: Windows, Linux, Ubuntu
- Web tools: CSS, HTML, java script.
- Android app development Android studio

Soft Skills

- Eager to learn new technologies and methodologies.
- Ability to work well within a team and individually.
- Good written and verbal communication skills.
- Strong motivational and leadership skills.

Academic projects

Corporate Communication Network and Stock Price Movements: Insights from Data Mining

Aim of the project is to find out the stock price movements of company through previous emails exchange of employees. So, we executed different Data mining algorithms and got to know that a corporate e-mail ecosystem contains meaningful information's about communication patterns which can reveal important information about major corporate activates and organizational stability that may subsequently influence the focal company performance in stock market.

Detection of Malicious URL using Deep LSTM Neural network

Machine learning methods have been used for feature-based analysis of data. Detection of such URLs with low False positive rate is a challenging task. In this work, we are using the Deep LSTM neural network to improve the classification performance. Along with the LSTM neural network, we have also implemented 4 different machine learning models as a proof of concept. Using LSTM neural network, the highest accuracy of 97.82% and PRF score of 0.98 have been achieved.

Certifications

- Cambridge English: Business Vantage (BEC Vantage)
- Augmented Reality IIT Bombay
- Full Stack Web Developer Udemy (Pursuing)